<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Migration on blog</title>
    <link>/tags/migration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Migration on blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/migration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I moved my website from Wordpress to GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>/2018/07/29/how-i-moved-my-website-from-wordpress-to-github-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/07/29/how-i-moved-my-website-from-wordpress-to-github-pages/</guid>
      <description>During my PhD, I created a personal academic website built with Wordpress and hosted by HostGator in order to establish my online presence. I then started blogging here and there about software programs, and eventually R code etc., that I was using or found helpful when conducting evolutionary genetic analyses for my previous or ongoing collaborations.
That all started around seven years ago.
I could write a lot about what I learned from using Wordpress (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate-N and phylogeography: Bayesian priors and run settings</title>
      <link>/2011/09/13/migrate-n-and-phylogeography-bayesian-priors-and-run-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 14:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/13/migrate-n-and-phylogeography-bayesian-priors-and-run-settings/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I discussed using Migrate-N for phylogeography (e.g. migration model testing, run settings, general tips). I mentioned that Migrate-N runs maximum likelihood (ML) and Bayesian algorithms and I discussed those a little bit, including how to run under different estimation modes. While Bayesian analysis is likely to be preferred for several reasons, a common critique of Bayesian methods in statistical population genetics and elsewhere is that it is difficult to set the prior information for each run.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>