<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Molecular Evolution on blog</title>
    <link>/categories/molecular-evolution/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Molecular Evolution on blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 19:52:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/molecular-evolution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting DNA substitution models in BEAST</title>
      <link>/2016/10/11/setting-dna-substitution-models-beast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 19:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/10/11/setting-dna-substitution-models-beast/</guid>
      <description>JC model of sequence evolution from TreeThinkers.
BEAST (Bayesian Evolutionary Analysis Sampling Trees) software provides a growing set of clear options for specifying evolutionary models of DNA substitution for alignments loaded into the program. However, the set of models that are readily available and &amp;ldquo;spelled out&amp;rdquo; in drop-down menus in the BEAUti (Bayesian Evolutionary Analysis Utility) GUI is much smaller compared to the standard set of 11 substitution schemes considered by other software programs for model selection (giving rise to a total of 88 models in jModelTest, or 56 models in PartitionFinder).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting trait-dependent shifts in DNA sequence evolution with traitRate</title>
      <link>/2015/09/17/detecting-trait-dependent-shifts-dna-sequence-evolution-traitrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 15:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/09/17/detecting-trait-dependent-shifts-dna-sequence-evolution-traitrate/</guid>
      <description>These days, we evo-biologists studying macroevolution tend to be interested in riding different waves of research and methods, and one of these is focused on understanding shifts in diversification rates as inferred from phylogenies and trait data. This is a hot topic in my opinion, and the focus is on understanding the causes and rates of spectacular adaptive and non-adaptive radiations of species in different systems across the glob.
But did you know it was possible to test for trait-dependent shifts in evolution of species DNA sequences or genomes?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>