<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mesquite on blog</title>
    <link>/tags/mesquite/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mesquite on blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 13:58:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mesquite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Mesquite with plugin for reading and writing NeXML format</title>
      <link>/2015/08/23/update-mesquite-plugin-reading-writing-nexml-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 13:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/23/update-mesquite-plugin-reading-writing-nexml-format/</guid>
      <description>In case you were unaware, there is a community-driven &amp;ldquo;NeXML&amp;rdquo; movement in computational phylogenetics, led by several bioinformaticians including Rutger Vos who are attempting to harness technologies and advantages of the XML format for transforming NEXUS flat files (an older standard for storing systematic data) into a format that is more easily processed and manipulated. See NeXML.org for more info on this technology and for softwares that allow reading and writing NeXML etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical phylogeography tutorial #1: Coalescent simulations in Mesquite Part I</title>
      <link>/2011/09/22/statistical-phylogeography-tutorial-1-coalescent-simulations-in-mesquite-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 16:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/22/statistical-phylogeography-tutorial-1-coalescent-simulations-in-mesquite-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Part I. Draft 9/22/11
WARNING: The following is based on my current understanding and use of Mesquite to perform coalescent simulations for phylogeographical hypotheses testing and is correct to the best of my knowledge, but I do not guarantee its accuracy. Also, you may not perform these analyses in the exact way or order that I have performed them. The following is based on a number of previously-published studies (e.g. Knowles 2001; Knowles &amp;amp; Maddison 2002; Carstens et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One way to evaluate incomplete lineage sorting in your phylogenetic or phylogeographic data</title>
      <link>/2011/07/19/one-way-to-evaluate-incomplete-lineage-sorting-in-your-phylogenetic-or-phylogeographic-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 04:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/19/one-way-to-evaluate-incomplete-lineage-sorting-in-your-phylogenetic-or-phylogeographic-data/</guid>
      <description>There aren&amp;rsquo;t many ways to quantitatively evaluate incomplete lineage sorting (ILS) or ancestral polymorphism in molecular data in a statistically rigorous way. One means of gauging relative amounts of lineage sorting is the gsi, which I will be working on later. But, right here I wanted to note that I recently saw Ian Wang &amp;amp; Brad Shaffer using Wayne Maddison and Lacey Knowles method to evaluate ILS in a paper they wrote on dendrobatid frogs of Costa Rica, which is one of the main areas I am studying in my dissertation research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>