<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Migrate N on blog</title>
    <link>/categories/migrate-n/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Migrate N on blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 14:56:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/migrate-n/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate-N and phylogeography: Bayesian priors and run settings</title>
      <link>/2011/09/13/migrate-n-and-phylogeography-bayesian-priors-and-run-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2011 14:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/13/migrate-n-and-phylogeography-bayesian-priors-and-run-settings/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I discussed using Migrate-N for phylogeography (e.g. migration model testing, run settings, general tips). I mentioned that Migrate-N runs maximum likelihood (ML) and Bayesian algorithms and I discussed those a little bit, including how to run under different estimation modes. While Bayesian analysis is likely to be preferred for several reasons, a common critique of Bayesian methods in statistical population genetics and elsewhere is that it is difficult to set the prior information for each run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use MIGRATE-N for phylogeography</title>
      <link>/2010/09/04/how-to-use-migrate-n-for-phylogeography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2010 00:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/09/04/how-to-use-migrate-n-for-phylogeography/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to MIGRATE-N One thing that makes this a great time to be involved in phylogeography is the exploding amount of data and quantitative methods available to workers. An important advance in the past 10 years has been the introduction of likelihood- and Bayesian inference-based methods for modeling gene flow, and for comparing models of gene flow, in population genetics. In particular, model-based coalescent methods are highly attractive. A method (or class of methods) that stems from statistical population genetics and is useful in phylogeography involves using coalescent gene genealogy samplers to estimate parameters based on variation across a huge number of gene trees representing estimates of probable ancestral patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>