<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on blog</title>
    <link>/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 18:23:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Setup A Linux Supercomputer for RAD-seq</title>
      <link>/2017/09/17/linux-supercomputer-rad-seq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 18:23:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/17/linux-supercomputer-rad-seq/</guid>
      <description>Here, I&amp;rsquo;m sharing a Gist that I recently wrote, and just updated today, about setting up an account on a Linux supercomputer for analyzing RAD-seq data (e.g. from ddRAD-seq, 2bRAD methods).
Here&amp;rsquo;s the Gist&amp;hellip;
https://gist.github.com/justincbagley/84f5dae6f35926c0c30bfc1cbd82eb24
Cheers ~J</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting BEAST2 Path Sampler analyses running on Windows 10</title>
      <link>/2017/08/17/getting-beast2-path-sampler-analyses-running-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 18:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/17/getting-beast2-path-sampler-analyses-running-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>BEAST2 PathSampler
I am a relatively big Mac (UNIX) and Linux fan, as many of you know. So, my standard approach to running BEAST or BEAST2 is to use my Mac for local setup and testing and then employ shell scripts (effective wrappers) that I&amp;rsquo;ve developed to automate final run setup and queuing on a Linux supercomputing cluster. However, there are times, especially when running path sampling (PS) analysis (Larillot and Phillipe 2006; Baele et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting BEAST v1.8.3 running! Beagle, CUDA, Java, and LINUX</title>
      <link>/2016/03/10/getting-beast-v1-8-3-running-java-cuda-beagle-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 12:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/03/10/getting-beast-v1-8-3-running-java-cuda-beagle-linux/</guid>
      <description>OK, I recently posted here about the new BEAST v1.8.3 release to let people know it was available (just echoing the announcement from Andrew Rambaut). Not sure about you, but when I get ahold of a new version of BEAST, I generally get it set up in my file system and try to run it. It&amp;rsquo;s good to go into this type of thing with a little dose of skepticism, as in my experience new versions of BEAST contain bug fixes but also seem to introduce new bugs or problems that you can run into.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BEASTGen: a new program for creating NEXUS, FASTA and BEAST XML input files for phylogenetics software</title>
      <link>/2013/10/29/beastgen-a-new-program-for-creating-nexus-fasta-and-beast-xml-input-files-for-phylogenetics-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 15:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/10/29/beastgen-a-new-program-for-creating-nexus-fasta-and-beast-xml-input-files-for-phylogenetics-software/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Rambaut has released the first version of a new software program, BEASTGen, that transforms phylogenetic data between the standard NEXUS, FASTA and BEAST XML formats. Could this mean that we are one step closer to calming many graduate students&amp;rsquo; (and other people&amp;rsquo;s) woes over this issue?
The new software can be downloaded from the BEAST Google code website, at https://code.google.com/p/beast-mcmc/downloads/detail?name=BEASTGen_v1.0.tgz.
Andrew has also written a brief set of instructions that can be found on the BEAST website, at http://beast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>