<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Terminal on blog</title>
    <link>/tags/terminal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Terminal on blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 15:22:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/terminal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to kill an R process without forcing R to quit on mac</title>
      <link>/2016/04/06/kill-r-process-without-forcing-r-quit-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 15:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/04/06/kill-r-process-without-forcing-r-quit-mac/</guid>
      <description>From time to time, we make mistakes in programming or testing a new R script or function, only to find that R &amp;ldquo;freezes&amp;rdquo; and appears to be stuck, or working but giving the impression that it will take an eternity to complete the computation. What could be happening is that the process is based on an maximum-likelihood estimation of a parameter that requires convergence, you could have accidentally (e.g. by default) run a function that needs to visit the total number of models possible for your dataset or a certain amount of parameter space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative ways to quickly get post-burnin trees from BEAST output from the command line</title>
      <link>/2014/12/26/quickly-get-post-burnin-trees-beast-output-without-using-log-combiner-tree-annotator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 11:06:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/26/quickly-get-post-burnin-trees-beast-output-without-using-log-combiner-tree-annotator/</guid>
      <description>Evolutionary biologists generally use nice java-written utility programs that come in the standard BEAST distribution to obtain post-burnin trees for summarizing the results of a converged BEAST run (or *BEAST run) that reached stationarity. Usually, only 5,000 to 20,000 trees are necessary for this, and these are typically obtained by cutting out &amp;lsquo;burnin&amp;rsquo; trees and then &amp;ldquo;thinning&amp;rdquo; trees from &amp;ldquo;.trees&amp;rdquo; output files using LogCombiner until the desired number of trees is reached.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give your mac some relief: how to remove the sleepimage file using Terminal</title>
      <link>/2014/09/20/give-mac-relief-remove-sleepimage-file-using-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 19:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/20/give-mac-relief-remove-sleepimage-file-using-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Your mac, depending on how you have it set up and how you use it, can slow on start up from restarts or hibernation due to the presence of a very large file called &amp;ldquo;sleepimage&amp;rdquo;. This is a very important file generated by Safe Sleep (on all MacBook Pros, for example) that serves the purpose of saving a state of your mac&amp;rsquo;s memory that keeps you from losing data when the computer sleeps, hibernates, restarts, or runs out of memory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>