<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Memory on blog</title>
    <link>/tags/memory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Memory on blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 23:17:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/memory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>dDocent install successes &amp; failures on Linux supercomputers</title>
      <link>/2018/03/10/ddocent-install-successes-failures-on-linux-supercomputers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 23:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/10/ddocent-install-successes-failures-on-linux-supercomputers/</guid>
      <description>Jon Puritz and some other developers have hacked out a nice pipeline, named dDocent (pronounced &amp;ldquo;docent&amp;rdquo;), for genomic assembly, read mapping, and SNP calling using NGS data from the RAD-seq family of sequencing strategies. dDocent is nice because it pulls together several top-of-the-line existing tools, and because it provides reference-based and de novo assembly options.
Instructions for installing dDocent are given at the pipeline&amp;rsquo;s Bioconda Download and Install page, and are claimed to be &amp;ldquo;So easy your grandfather could do this&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give your mac some relief: how to remove the sleepimage file using Terminal</title>
      <link>/2014/09/20/give-mac-relief-remove-sleepimage-file-using-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 19:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/20/give-mac-relief-remove-sleepimage-file-using-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Your mac, depending on how you have it set up and how you use it, can slow on start up from restarts or hibernation due to the presence of a very large file called &amp;ldquo;sleepimage&amp;rdquo;. This is a very important file generated by Safe Sleep (on all MacBook Pros, for example) that serves the purpose of saving a state of your mac&amp;rsquo;s memory that keeps you from losing data when the computer sleeps, hibernates, restarts, or runs out of memory.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>